Guide to the Rutherfurd Collection 1642-1845 MS 531
New-York Historical Society
- Series I: Correspondence and Documents, 1642-1845 (bulk 1734-1796)
  - Subseries I.G: Volume VI, 1792-1803
    - [62] I have been quite..., 1794 August 10
    - [62] Three excellent mowers..., 1794 August 17
    - [63] We expect this will..., 1794 December 3
    - [63] We were much..., 1794 December 24
    - [64] In a vast hury..., 1795 January 2
    - [64] We were happy..., 1795 March 17
    - [65] As congress dissolves..., 1795 April 25
    - [65] We received yours..., 1795 April 25
    - [66] We long to hear of..., 1795 May 4
    - [66] I am happy to..., 1795 May 20
    - [67] We found the roads..., 1795 August 16
    - [67] After a pleasant..., 1795 August 27
    - [68] To be sold at vendue..., 1795 October 24
    - [68] I had prepared..., 1795 October 31
    - [69] By mistake I thought..., 1795 December 4
    - [69] St. Andrews Day- Hope this will find you..., 1795
    - [70] We were much disappointed..., 1796 December 11
    - [70] The great, and fatiquing..., 1795 November 13
    - [71] At last we find..., 1795 December 18
    - [71] With deep concern..., 1795 December 22
    - [72] We were happy..., 1795 December 30
    - [72] With much satisfaction..., 1795 December 30
    - [72] We long to hear from..., 1796 January 8
    - [73] We received yours on..., 1796 February 21
    - [73] We have received yours..., 1796 March 29
    - [74] To let be..., 1796 April 7
    - [74] Recd yours of Sunday..., 1796 April 9
    - [75] With much satisfaction..., 1796 April 22
    - [75] Yours of Saturday..., 1796
    - [76] Arrived Saturday..., 1796 June 14
    - [76] We have not heard..., 1796 May 15
    - [76] I had some..., 1796 May 22
    - [77] We were glad..., 1796 June 9
    - [77] Hope you heard..., 1796 June 27
    - [78] We were glad to..., 1796 September 12
    - [78] Recd yours with..., 1796 September 18
    - [79] The Weekly Intelligencer..., 1796 October 2
    - [79] We were much..., 1796 October 23
    - [80] By yours we are glad..., 1796 December 12
    - [80] We wish you and our..., 1796 December 25
    - [81] We congratulate you..., 1797 January 1
    - [82] Receipt, 1784 December 20
    - [82] We received your of..., 1797 February 10
    - [82] Not hearing lately..., 1797 January 30
    - [83] It is a long time..., 1787 March 3
    - [83] We received yours..., 1797 March 12
    - [84] I am ashamed..., 1797 April 7
    - [84] We did not hear..., 1797 February 20
    - [84] We were happy to..., 1797 March 26
    - [85] Fortunately..., 1797 April 9
    - [85] Never came more..., 1797 April 17
    - [86] I wrote a long, 1797 April 21
    - [86] I hope you heard..., 1797 April 24
    - [87] We were disappointed, 1797 April 30
    - [87] We expect this, 1797 May 14
    - [88] At least we have, 1787 June 5
    - [88] Steel has been, 1797 June 12
    - [88] Yesterday the Governor, 1797 June 22
    - [88] We have long expected, 1797 May 28
    - [89] We are much concerned, 1797 July 17
    - [89] June 28 We received yours of, Undated
    - [90] Last evening at 1/2, 1797 July 31
    - [90] We were much, 1797 September 2
    - [91] We made a very, 1797 September 17
    - [91] We received yours, 1797 September 22
    - [92] We were again much, 1797 October 8
    - [92] Soon after I, 1797 October 15
    - [92] Yours of the 10th, 1797 October 22
    - [92] We received Mary R's, 1797 October 29
    - [93] It gives us great, 1797 November 14
    - [93] Mr. Morris, 1797 November 21
    - [94] We are glad to hear, 1797 December 5
    - [94] We have received, 1797 November 28
    - [95] We give you all joy, 1797 December 12
    - [95] We were disappointed, 1797 December 19
    - [96] We received your last, 1797 December 26
    - [96] This family sends, 1798 January 2
    - [96] We hope Pero, 1798 January 9
    - [97] No letter this week, 1798 January 23
    - [98] I'm thankful, 1798 February 12
    - [98] We received, 1798 February 12
    - [98] Half past 9, 1798 February 26
    - [100] I found all well, 1798 April 9
    - [100] Yours came as it, 1798 March 6
    - [101] No letter since, 1798 April 17
    - [101] Again no letter, 1798 April 24
    - [102] We hope we have the, 1798 June 5
    - [102] We have received yours, 1798 June 11
    - [102] Probably this will, 1798 May 8
    - [102] Yours of 19th April, 1798 May
- Series II: Scrapbooks, 1642-1794
  The contents of Series II were originally bound into 2 scrapbooks, which included a large and a small scrapbook. The items were unbound during conservation, but maintain their original order. The page number of each item is indicated in brackets.
  Series II is available on microfilm.
  - Subseries II.A: Large Scrapbook, 1756-1794
    - [1] As you promised, 1756 February 27
    - [3] I have two, 1758 July 9
    - [5] I had almost, 1758 July 28
    - [7] When I received, 1758 September 15
    - [7] Captain Chevallier, 1759 October 28
    - [9] I wrote you, 1759 November 2
    - [9] I have received, 1760 October 8
    - [11] I have been wishing, 1761 April 17
    - [11]It is about a, 1761 September 6
    - [13] Many thanks, 1762 February 12
    - [13] I take the first, 1762 October 29
    - [15] It is a long time, 1763 April 22
    - [15] I wrote to you, 1762 December 14
    - [17] I wrote to you, 1763 June 16
    - [19] I wrote to you, 1763 June 16
    - [21] I have before one, 1763 December
    - [23] I have before one, 1763 December 31
    - [23] I wrote you a, 1764 January 31
    - [25] I wrote you, 1764 January 31
    - [27] I send you the, 1764 February 17
    - [29] I wrote you a very, 1764 March 2
    - [31] The distress, 1764 March 23
    - [35] I had the pleasure, 1764 May 18
    - [39] Captain Patrick Dennis, 1764 July 16
    - [41] The Johanna Capt, 1765 January 1
    - [45] The want of opportunitys, 1765 July 19
    - [47] It is with much, 1766 March 15
    - [49] We now think that, 1766 August 19
    - [51] This will be delivered, 1766 August 28
    - [53] It gives me the, 1766 December 19
    - [55] I acknowledge, 1766 December 31
    - [57] I received on the 14th, 1767 January 26
    - [59] I have many thanks, 1767 February 25
    - [61] I have duely received, 1767 February 27
    - [63] I had the pleasure of, 1767 March 28
    - [65] We advised you, 1767 March 28
    - [67] I had the pleasure, 1767 March 28
    - [69] Your very kind, 1767 August 24
    - [69] The prices of, Undated
    - [71] The pleasure I have, 1769 June 12
    - [72] What excuses can, 1772 December 4
    - [73] I should have, 1773 October 1
    - [75] Your friend, 1778 July 25
    - [77] Some months ago, 1779 April 6
    - [79] I wrote you a, 1779 June 23
    - [81] I received with, 1780 March 3
    - [83] Your very kind, 1782 April 22
    - [85] It is quite, 1782 October 19
    - [87] I blush at taking, 1784 February 2
    - [89] I never thought, 1784 August 24
    - [91] Since I wrote you, 1786 June 1
    - [91] I have often, 1785 June 29
    - [93] Our worthy sister, 1787 March 15
    - [95] On seeing your, 1786 September 4
    - [97] I wrote to you, 1787 May 25
    - [99] I have to thank, 1788 February 29
    - [101] Your very kind, 1788 October 28
    - [103] I have more than, 1790 February 28
    - [105] I wrote you a, 1790 March 27
    - [107] Since my last, 1790 August 27
    - [109] I am quite ashamed, 1791 May 27
    - [109] I am quite ashamed, 1792 November 26
    - [111] I wrote you a, 1793 January 26
    - [113] It is with the greatest, 1794 March 1
    - [121] Though not in a, Undated
    - [123] As I am going, 1785 August 10
    - [118-119?] Receipt L100, 1746 January 31
    - [151] Within these two hours, 1750 January 27
    - [163] I intebd this by, 1753 December 21
    - [193] My not hearing for, 1765 August 17
    - [99?] Messrs Murray [memo], 1743 September 9
  - Subseries II.B: Small Scrapbook, 1642-1830 (bulk 1704-1760)
    - [1] Emporium newspaper loose, 1830 October 9
    - [1] Colonel Lovelaw, 1673 May 24
    - [2] In the name of God (copy), 1642 December 10
    - [3] Propositions, 1699
    - [4] Councills Opinion, Undated
    - [5] Know all men, 1704 November 20
    - [6] I had not a line, 1710 July 26
    - [7] Receipt, 1712 May 14
    - [8] Carriages, 1775
    - [8] What you write, 1714 September 13
    - [9] I have appointed, 1715 January 3
    - [10] Mr Seabring, 1714 February 1
    - [11] I am much obliged, 1714 December 20
    - [12] I am spoke to by, 1716 October 8
    - [13] I forgot to tell you, 1716 February 13
    - [14] Petition of John Rockhead, Undated
    - [15] I have receiv'd, 1717 May 20
    - [16] I have, 1717 May 20
    - [17] I had yours, 1718 September 22
    - [18] Be it remembered, 1719 May 12
    - [19] It is impossible, 1719 October 12
    - [20] My Attendance, 1721 June
    - [21] Its now a long, 1721 October 20
    - [22] The Hurry, 1722 January 4
    - [23] I have the favour, 1722 August 8
    - [24] I have the pleasure, 1723 June 10
    - [25] I am very glad, 1723 November 21
    - [26] Your commission, 1724 February 25
    - [27] I recd yours of, 1724 October 31
    - [28] I have not, 1724 August 29
    - [29] I thank you, 1725 November 21
    - [30] The Bearer hearof, 1725 March 13
    - [31] Inclos'd is a letter, 1717 February 12
    - [32] In the Name of God, 1706 April 5
    - [33] draft of Dunster will, 1727 June 24
    - [34] Michael Kearney, 1727 June 24
    - [35] Copy of Dunster will, 1724 September 1
    - [36] Resolved that, 1725 June 10
    - [37] Soon after my return, 1729 September 15
    - [38] A coppy of minutes, 1728 January
    - [39] Its near a week, 1730 August 6
    - [40] The case of Gen'l Hunter, Undated
    - [41] As to the contents, 1730 January 4
    - [42] In complyance with, 1730 January 18
    - [43] copies of letters, from Paris, 1730
    - [44] I reced the favour, 1731 January 31
    - [45] I had the favour of, 1731 January 21
    - [46] I send the list of, 1731 March 20
    - [47] Since my last of the, 1731 January 21
    - [48] I have not heard, 1731 May 24
    - [49] My last, 1731 April 27
    - [50] Having but a very, 1731 July 31
    - [51] We had three days, 1731 July 29
    - [52] Twas as only, 1731 April 15
    - [53] My last to you, 1731 August 17
    - [54] We had the favour, 1732 September 20
    - [55] Beg the favour, 1733 March 27
    - [56] According as I, 1733 May 18
    - [57] There having been, 1733 May 29
    - [58] On the 29th of May, 1733 August 31
    - [59] I just now reced, 1734 February 5
    - [60] Memorandum, 1734 November 30
    - [61] I have Hear, 1735 January 13
    - [62] I have your favour, 1735 February 21
    - [63] memo, Undated
    - [64] I am desired by, 1735 August 1
    - [65] I am informed that, 1735 October 1
    - [66] I have your favour, 1735 October 17
    - [67] Since mine to you, 1735 November 21
    - [68] We heartily, 1763 April 10
    - [69] Sir the bearer hereof, 1736 November 15
    - [70] My wifes Condition, 1736 October 15
    - [71] Yesterday I, 1738 July 22
    - [72] I have your, 1737 July 25
    - [73] In an action, 1739 February 13
    - [74] Since our letter, 1741 August 20
    - [75] James Alexander, 1741 December 23
    - [76] Inclosed is a copy, 1741 August 27
    - [77] Yours without date, 1741 June 16
    - [78] Gabriel Stelle, 1741 September 16
    - [79] I think you told me, 1741 December 4
    - [80] I return to you my, 1741 December 23
    - [81] This day I sett out, 1742 October 19
    - [82] Col. Hamilton, 1741 January 12
    - [83] We have a letter, 1742 January 7
    - [84] Before you have, 1742 January 18
    - [85] Inclosed you have, 1741 December 22
    - [86] I send you an old, 1742 June 20
    - [87] No doubt, 1742 June 20
    - [88] The Council, 1742 November 22
    - [89] I recd yours by, 1742 November 25
    - [90] I had the favour, 1742 December 6
    - [91] It was with great, 1742 December 6
    - [92] The Councill of, 1742 December 20
    - [93] Under this cover, 1742 December 20
    - [94] I have taken the, 1742 December 23
    - [95] I recd a Letter, 1742 December 25
    - [96] I had yours of the 12th, 1742 January 16
    - [97] I was not a little, 1743 January 19
    - [98] you know there's a, Undated
    - [100] I was at Elizabeth, 1743 November 16
    - [101] Yours with the copy, 1743 December 12
    - [102] I have the favour, 1743 January 24
    - [103] William Bradford, 1743 April 15
    - [104] The foregoing, 1743 June 24
    - [105] Inclosed you have, 1743 December 5
    - [106] Last Thursday, 1743 November 24
    - [107] By Mr Jonathan, 1743 December 26
    - [108] I herewith send, 1744 November 10
    - [109] I have only just, 1745 March 14
    - [110] Yours of the 25th, 1745 July 8
    - [111] I have yours of the, 1745 April 30
    - [112] Trusty and Welbeloved, copy, 1745 September 19
    - [113] Trusty and Welbeloved, copy, 1745 September 20
    - [114] Trusty and Welbeloved, copy, 1745 September 21
    - [115] Trusty and Welbeloved, copy, 1745 September 23
    - [116] Trusty and Welbeloved, copy, 1745 September 25
    - [117] Mr. Barclay, 1746 May 2
    - [118] My last was of the, 1746 May 26
    - [119] Receipt L100, 1746 January 31
    - [120] I write you Duplicates, 1746 January 27
    - [121] I am now able to, 1746 February 10
    - [122] On the 10th instant, 1746 February 13
    - [123] This day I moved, 1747 May 15
    - [124] As we had in effect, 1747 April 15
    - [125] We have received, 1747 May 26
    - [126] A coppy, Undated
    - [127] I recd your printed, 1747 July 23
    - [128] I suppose you have, 1747 July 25
    - [129] I was just, 1747 July
    - [130] To the Rt Honble, 1747 August
    - [131] My last to you, 1747 August 13
    - [132] For the General Proprietors, Undated
    - [133] We heartily, 1747 December
    - [134] My last letters, 1747 October 17
    - [135] By this Post, 1747 October 30
    - [136] By Mr Carter, 1747 January 26
    - [137] By Mr Burbeen, 1748 February 10
    - [138] Some weeks ago, 1748 February 22
    - [139] A friend at Burlington, 1748 February 19
    - [140] At the first, 1748 February 18
    - [141] On the 26th of Jan, 1748 March 9
    - [142] Advertisement, 1748 March 23
    - [143] Your letters of the 21st, 1748 March 25
    - [144] I had the favour, 1748 May 5
    - [145] On looking over my, 1748 September 1
    - [146] Tho I am Obliged, 1748 June 4
    - [146A] Queries from the Board of Trade, Undated
    - [147] On the 28th of last, 1748 January 17
    - [148] the... man of war, 1750 August 2
    - [149] know all men, 1749 May 23
    - [150] Instructions relating, 1749
    - [152] I am to acknowledge, 1751 April 11
    - [153] As a Law of this, 1750 December 28
    - [154] Yesterday I heard, 1751 August 28
    - [155] On the 14th instant, 1752 March 24
    - [156] I hear by give you, Undated
    - [157] I send duplicates, 1753 August 18
    - [158] Being under great, 1753 August 20
    - [159] I pray your favor, 1753 August 22
    - [160] Your kind favour, 1753 January 24
    - [161] By virtue of an, 1752 February 20
    - [162] After finishing, 1753 October 26
    - [164] I take the liberty, 1754 March 29
    - [165] As I hear Capt, 1754 April 10
    - [166] As I intend to go, 1754 June 4
    - [167] I am come thus farr, 1754 June 2
    - [168] I wrote you from, 1754 June 9
    - [169] Expecting that, 1754 July 12
    - [170] By a Letter from, 1754 August 13
    - [171] Map, 1754
    - [172] Before is coppy, 1754 September 5
    - [173] in a Separate, 1754
    - [174] The representation, 1754 March
    - [175] On the 16th Instant, 1754 July 29
    - [176] Your favour of, 1754 October 8
    - [177] My last was of, 1754 December 16
    - [178] Yesterday I, 1754 November 26
    - [179] herewith you have, 1754 December 2
    - [180] I wrote to you, 1755 January 2
    - [181] I rec'd yours, 1755 May 11
    - [182] yours of Decr 16th, 1755 June 7
    - [183] I send to you, 1755 August 11
    - [184] I have but a, 1755 August 7
    - [185] The Province of New Jersey, 1755
    - [186] Account to Livingston & Alexander, Undated
    - [187] Invoice, 1755 May 9
    - [188] This comes by a, 1755 December 2
    - [189] Col Schuyler was Taken, Undated
    - [190] About 3 weeks ago, 1759 August 18
    - [191] Please to send me, 1759 December 6
    - [192] I thank you for, 1760 January 18
- Series III: Genealogy, Printed Material, and Account Book, 1650-1939
  This series consists of genealogical material, volumes owned by various members of the family, and an account book. The final volume of the sub-series contains blank pages.
  - Family Records and Events by Livingston Rutherfurd. New York: the De Vinne Press, 1894 (Volume 13)
  - Descendants of Lewis Morris of Morrisania, compiled by Elizabeth Morris Lefferts, Undated (Volume 14)
  - The Flowers of Shakespeare, given to Miss L.M. Rutherfurd, 1846 (Volume 15)
  - "History Naturall and Experimentall of Life and Death or Of the Prolongation of Life", "Sylva Sylvarum: A Natural History in Ten Centuries"; and "New Atlantis, A Work Unfinished", bound together, 1650, 1651 by Francis Bacon (Volume 16)
    Autograph: "Lewis Morris his Booke 1679"
  - John Peter Zenger His Press, His Trial and a Bibliography of Zenger Imprints by Livingston Rutherfurd, 1904 (Volume 17)
  - The Constitution and Nominations of the Subscribers to the Tontine Coffee-House. New York: Printed in the Year 1796 (Volume 18)
  - Cardboard autograph album, 1770-1800, 1927-1939 (Volume 19)
  - Account book, 1844-1852 (Volume 20)
  - Blank volume, Undated (Volume 21)
    Volume containing blank pages and labeled "Volume VII"